Artur Vanivskyi - Software Developer

New York, NY | 646-830-9748 | vanivskyi.artur@gmail.com | Linkedin | GitHub | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full-Stack software engineer proficient in using JavaScript for front-end and back-end programming, React, HTML, CSS, API implementing, Node.JS, Express, PostgreSQL, and frameworks like Bootstrap. Problem solver with experience developing logical and methodical solutions to problems. A keen eye for design, allowing for the development of visually pleasing and user-friendly website designs.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, jQuery.

Backend: Node.js, Express, RESTful APIs, PostgreSQL, GoLang, C++.

Tools: Mocha, Chai, Knex, Git, GitHub, Heroku, Node Package Manager, Visual Studio Code.

Additional Skills: Ukrainian (fluent), Russian (fluent), Polish (Intermediate).

EXPERIENCE

X-line Glass&Mirror Remote

Freelance Frontend Developer | Link

11/2022 - 02/2023

- Designed and developed a responsive, single-page website for X-line Glass&Mirror company using JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and Swiper.is.
- Ensured the website was optimized for both desktop and mobile devices using responsive design techniques.
- Utilized Swiper.js to create a dynamic and interactive user experience.
- Currently maintaining and updating the website to ensure smooth performance and functionality.

Thinkful Full-Stack Engineering Student

Remote 06/2022 - 11/2022

- Learned industry best practices and software development standards with a focus on JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, React Native, Node.is, PostgreSQL, RESTful APIs, algorithms, and data structures.
- Developed and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks, spending several hours per week collaborating with senior web developers in a mentor-student relationship.
- Produced professional projects from concept to completion including:
 - E-commerce: Crown Shop | Project Link
 - Developed an e-commerce platform with user-friendly interface to provide customers with easy access to products, with focus on front-end development.
 - Implemented sign-in and google sign-in functionality.
 - Integrated a payment component using Stripe to enable customers to securely make transactions.
 - Used serverless functions to connect front-end and Firebase.
 - Utilized Redux Saga to maintain clean state management in an e-commerce platform.
 - Technology: JavaScript, React, Redux, CSS and FireBase, Stripe. Version control with Git.
 - Restaurant Reservation System | Project Link
 - Full stack reservation and table management system.
 - Implemented react router and express to build a RESTful API in order to make HTTP requests for all of the reservation data stored on the connected PostgreSQL database.
 - Created CRUD functions and Knex gueries to handle data going to and coming from the database.
 - Used Git to track changes while keeping sensitive information from being pushed to repositories.
 - Technology: React, Node.js, Express, Knex and PostgreSQL.
 - BusinessCard Holder "Vancard" | Project Link
 - Full stack business card holder system.
 - Originated and applied CRUD functions and queries to manage sending and retrieving data in database.
 - Used Git to track changes while keeping sensitive information from being pushed to repositories.
 - Programmed react router and express to build RESTful API.
 - Technology: Node.js, Express, and Knex. Version control with Git.

Masal / Masal Plus
Brooklyn, NY
Manager
04/2018 - 08/2022

• Formulated pricing policies by reviewing merchandising activities, and determined needed sales promotions.

- Completed store operational requirements by scheduling and assigning employees, and followed up on results.
- Maintained store staff by recruiting, selecting, orienting, and training 40-50 employees.
- Prepared an annual budget and achieved financial objectives by saving an average of \$2500 per month.

GasInfoService Project Manager of Geology and Geophysics department

Ukraine 05/2016 - 08/2017

 Developed a database of various businesses which use and convey equipment used in the Geology and Geophysics surveys and closed 24 deals for the company, bringing in \$50K.

- Presented at conferences, pitching the company and its services, to gain new clients and partners.
- Built the structure for the web page in the Geology and Geophysics section, reviewing the JavaScript code.
- Introduced web-design for Geology and Geophysics section using Figma, Tailwind and JavaScript.

EDUCATION

Online Thinkful Certificate, Software Engineering 11/2022 AGH University of Science and Technology Cracow, Poland MS, Applied Geophysics 02/2017 Ivano-Frankivsk National Technical University of Oil and Gas Ivano-Frankivsk, Ukraine MS, Geophysics 02/2017 Ivano-Frankivsk, Ukraine Ivano-Frankivsk National Technical University of Oil and Gas **B.S.** Geology 06/2015